

### ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with nearly two decades of electronic communications and leadership experience. For the past 7 years, I have been self-motivated, consistently learning new skills within the IT industry to better serve both the companies I am on mission with, and the customers they support.

### EXPERIENCE

### **Software Developer**

Microsoft Software and Systems Academy | JBLM, WA | 2021 - Present

Developed multiple applications with C#, Python, and the web development stack
to solve various problem-solving tasks during both personal and class projects.
 Projects include the building of my personal website and creating open-source
ethical hacking tools.

### Lead Major Incident Manager/Sr. Engineer

Mindtree Limited | Redmond, WA | 2018 - Present

- Received multiple awards as a Team Influencer and High Performer by operating
  efficiently under high-stress situations during Major Incidents/Outages for
  Microsoft's core services.
- Improved Key Performance Indicators by up to 16% across all deliverables, notably bridge management, incident recordings, and executive-level communications.

# Azure Platforms Engineer/Premier Support

Mindtree Limited | Redmond, WA | 2017 - 2018

- Transformed the Azure Platforms Team leadership structure, producing multiple small group leaders and increasing overall management efficiency.
- Received over 97% Customer Satisfaction ratings across all support cases by providing cloud computing solutions to complex issues on the Azure platform.

#### **Junior Systems Administrator**

Olympic Eagle Distributing | Puyallup, WA | 2015 - 2017

- Received highest ratings across core competencies and values during performance review.
- Saved over \$350k per year in electronics maintenance costs by taking on maintenance projects that were previously outsourced.

# Senior Radio/Communications Security Repairer US Army | JBLM, WA | 2002 - 2014

- Led maintenance initiative at the brigade level raising the Communications and Electronics status from below 75% effective to over 90% in under 6 months.
- Received multiple awards for efforts in leadership, unit training initiatives, maintenance initiatives, and process improvement.

253.355.2924

john.s.cruz@outlook.com

**♥** Greater Seattle Area

LinkedIn.com/in/johnscruz

github.com/Cruz-S13

### SKILLS

C# Leadership Development
Python Change Management
TSQL C-Suite Communications
HTML Business Insights
CSS<sub>3</sub> Azure laaS Platform

JavaScript Infrastructure Management
Power BI Major Incident Management

# PROJECTS (Linked to GitHub)

**SeCure-ity** (bit.ly/SeCure-ity)

Python | Kali Linux | Metasploitable | Virtualization

- Collection of open source, ethical hacking tools

Crap-a-Dappa (bit.ly/Play-Craps)

C# | Object Oriented Programming

- Console app where users can learn how to play the Craps dice game.

# EDUCATION

# Certificate of Computer Science

Saint Martin's University Projected Graduation - 2021

**BAS: Network Security Administration** 

Green River College

2016 - 2017

AAS: Systems and Network Security

Clover Park Technical College

2014 - 2016